Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adopted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
I can cut a thousand strands of hair
but I cannot sever the tangled threads of my mind.
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For all the lovers in the world,
who can break the spell of romance?
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For all the lovers in the world,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
You are well-versed in poetry.
Zhen Yuandao taught his daughter well.
I wonder if you live up to this name.
Raise your head.
The name "Zhen" is an offense against the Emperor.
[His name is Yin Zhen]
Your Majesty, when my father became an official,
the prior emperor commended the name "Zhen".
He said this name connotes loyalty,
and to keep it as an encouragement.
I understand the prior emperor.
Imperial Mother, this reminds me of
the beauties of the Three Kingdoms Period:
"Lady Zhen north of the Yellow River,
and the two Qiaos south of the Yangtze."
The Zhens are known for their beautiful ladies.
Lady Zhen was one of the Three Beauties in the Eastern Han dynasty.
Come forward.
You carry yourself well.
“Slim-waisted and delicate are the slender beauties in King Chu's palace.
In springtime they wither, as flowers losing luster and fragrance."
But the winds and waters of my palace are nourishing.
You will not "wither like flowers."
Who is the other lady next to her?
Sun Miaoqing, age sixteen, sister of Sun Zhuhe,
the Chief of Suzhou Clothing Services.
Sun Miaoqing lost her manners before Her Majesty.
Take her out. She shall never attend another Selection.
Aye.
- Zhen Huan is selected. Bestow the sachet.
- Your Majesty, please forgive me!
Those who wished to stay have been dismissed,
while those who hoped for dismissal have remained.
Many people dream to be blessed with a life in the palace.
Don't sigh over it.
Besides, we will enter the palace together.
We can take care of each other.
The messenger eunuch must be on his way
to inform your parents. They will be overjoyed.
But Meizhuang, I had no intention of being selected.
I know you didn't, but it was Heaven's intention.
Heaven does not "cast a bright pearl into darkness."
But His Majesty...
Sun Miaoqing was simply startled.
She meant no offense.
The Son of Heaven commands weighty authority.
We must also carry ourselves with poise and stability.
Greetings, My Ladies.
I was instructed to conduct you to the gate, My Ladies.
I humbly congratulate you on becoming imperial concubines.
Here they come.
I wonder how it went.
Take care, Meizhuang.
You as well.
[list of selected candidates]
“The slender beauties in King Chu's palace.”
Your Majesty, the Empress requests an audience.
- Show her in.
- Yes, Your Majesty.
I came to congratulate Your Majesty on gaining
several beautiful ladies once again.
What makes you say so?
The palaces all heard that Your Majesty was very pleased today.
I was fortunate to come across a few adequate candidates
amidst the unremarkable crowds.
Not just adequate.
I heard that Shen Zishan's daughter bears some
resemblance of Concubine Estime.
And Miss Zhen looks exactly like ...
Just a little bit on the eyes and brows.
Even some likeness is extraordinary.
Pardon my asking, but what rank does Your Majesty
plan to grant Miss Zhen?
How about Noble Lady?
Noble Lady...
Sounds good. Noble Lady it is.
In this case, there will be four Noble Ladies:
Lady Fuca from the Manchu Banners,
Lady Borjigin from the Mongolian Banners,
and two from the Han Banners.
Two? Who is the other one?
Noble Lady Shen, daughter of Shen Zishan.
Her father's position is higher than Zhen's.
Your Majesty esteems the Han banners,
but the marriage alliance between Manchus and Mongolians is customary.
Couldn't two Noble Ladies in the Han Banners
catch a bit too much attention?
In that case, she will be an Attendant.
[one rank below Noble Lady]
It's not appropriate for Han banners
to have a high rank when they enter the palace.
Yes, Your Majesty.
However, I wish to give her an honorary name.
I will ask the Household Department to propose a name.
No, I already have one in mind.
Come here.
Sourire.
[meaning "smile"]
I remember this character from a Tang poem about the spring:
"The lush willows branch their silken threads;
The dense spring flowers droop their misted eyes."
The light smile on her face -
so pretty!
Vermilion, are we almost home?
Yes, My Lady. Look, what a lively crowd!
Here she comes!
I see her!
Congratulations!
Congratulations, Mr. Zhen!
Father.
Zhen Yuandao and family greets My Lady.
Peace to My Lady.
What are you doing?
Get up. Please get up!
My Lady, we must follow the protocol of greeting you.
My Lady, you are a member of the imperial family now.
Mr. Zhen is supposed to bow to you.
Exactly.
Vermilion and Jade, quickly, help my parents up.
Thank You, My Lady.
It's windy out here. Let's go inside.
After you, My Lady.
Mind your step.
I'm an unfilial daughter. I cannot serve my parents.
Please get up.
And I made my parents kneel to me.
My heart cannot rest easy.
- Please get up ...
- Please allow me to finish.
Although I've become a member of the imperial family,
I hope you will permit me to serve you
as your daughter before I enter the palace.
I'll kneel here until you allow me to fulfil my filial duties.
Certainly.
You never let me down as my daughter.
Please stand up. Get up now.
Your Highness is awake.
Her Highness rises.
[Fuzi]
As per Your Highness's inquiry,
His Majesty stayed with Attendant Joie last night.
His Majesty had not visited the harem for over ten days.
And that wretch was the first one he visited?
A month has already passed since her miscarriage.
Isn't a few days of feigned feelings enough?
Isn't she acting like a minx?
Idiot! Could you be any more careless?
I beg Your Highness's pardon.
How can you be so incompetent?
Are you deliberately hurting Her Highness?
Isn't that your intention? Is it?
Making "a ruckus of the fowls and dogs"
so early in the morning.
Take her out immediately!
Please spare me, Your Highness!
Come with me!
Please spare me! Your Highness!
Your Highness!
Move!
Please forgive me!
Your Majesty, it seems that Consort Fleur
won't come to pay her respects today.
Shall we adjourn now?
She is a consort
and she must pay respects to the Empress every morning.
We will wait however late she is.
Provide tea.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Spring, serve the tea.
She's the last one again.
Her brother is Great General Nian,
who is in the prime of his powers.
(Attendant Joie)
And His Majesty dotes on her so much.
(Consort Astuce)
She may be favored, but she's not the Empress.
(Noble Lady Cao)
I haven't seen Consort Honnête for quite some time.
Consort Honnête? She can hardly leave her bed most days.
(Concubine Estime, Concubine Beauté)
Consort Fleur is here.
Peace to Your Highness.
You may rise.
Attendant Joie is here early.
Has your health improved?
I thank Your Highness for asking.
I felt a little unwell from rising earlier,
but that cannot delay me from paying respects to Her Majesty.
That was thoughtful of you.
I hope you'll keep nourishing your health now the first month is past,
so you will soon be ready to carry another child for His Majesty.
I thank Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, although Attendant Joie still feels unwell,
her health has been much better than before.
I've noticed her healthy glow.
Consort Astuce's figure has filled out.
His Majesty will be delighted to see you.
Thank you for your kind words.
Oh, but I forgot.
His Majesty has not been visiting you.
I don't have a good memory. Please don't blame me.
It's all right.
We're all sisters here, we should not be standing while talking.
Please have a seat.
I thank Your Majesty.
Peace to Your Majesty.
Sit and have some tea.
Spring, tea for Her Highness.
Is this last year's Dragon Well tea?
Your Majesty still keeps it?
Old tea, however well stored,
still carries the smell of mildew.
I gave mine to my maids.
I have received this year's pre-rain Dragon Well.
I will tell Songzhi to bring some
so Your Majesty can have a taste.
Thank you, I have received some from His Majesty as well.
I thought the Third Prince would like it,
so I had it sent to Consort Astuce.
Of course,
it must be a rarity for Consort Astuce to receive such fine tea.
If the Third Prince needs anything else,
don't hesitate to ask me.
The Third Prince is a filial son.
He would not disturb His Majesty for trivial matters.
It's all owing to Consort Astuce's teaching.
The Third Prince has a filial heart indeed.
He surely will be studious to please His Majesty.
When His Majesty is pleased, he will award the Third Prince
not only leaves of tea, but even leaves of gold.
The Fourth Prince and the Fifth Prince are still young.
All the princes look up to the Third Prince
and he naturally has an exemplary character.
His Majesty took the throne so recently
that the palaces are not fully equipped.
Especially Your Majesty's Palace of Great Benevolence.
I intend to have it better embellished on a clear day
to create a more comfortable dwelling for Your Majesty.
I appreciate your thought.
It hasn't been long since His Majesty's enthronement.
Frugality is our prime consideration.
This matter can wait.
I admire your generous nature.
My Palace of Earthly Honor is too lavishly decorated.
Whenever I come here to pay my respects,
I always find myself ill at ease.
the Palace of Earthly Honor was occupied by
Consort Bonheur of the prior emperor.
That's why it is out of the ordinary.
Indeed. Consort Bonheur was greatly favored for being a prolific mother.
The hour is late.
I take my leave, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, I will retire as well.
I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
Consort Fleur is impertinent.
But Your Majesty always quiets her insolence with just a few words.
But she wasn't wrong.
The Palace of Great Benevolence may not be the most extravagant,
but it gathers good fortune and generous spirits.
(Autumn)
His Majesty specially granted it in honor of your benevolence
for Your Majesty to dwell in harmony.
Your Highness, don't be angry.
The Empress was just jealous of our palace.
Consort Bonheur was favored for having many children.
But her son's rebellion implicated her.
How dare she curse me this way?
Your Highness must not take that to heart.
That sickly Empress wouldn't dare to compete with you.
Whoever begrudges Your Highness's favor
is disrespecting His Majesty.
You know quite a lot.
I know nothing but Your Highness is
at the very center of His Majesty's heart.
Indeed.
Your Highness resides in the Palace of Earthly Honor.
It is the only palace in the harem that represents the Earth,
like the ceremonial Palace of Earthly Tranquility.
Evidently, His Majesty sees Your Highness as his Empress.
His Majesty's respect for the Empress is only a matter of ceremony.
Your Highness takes priority.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
We've arrived.
Is this the sister of Miss Zhen?
No, Jade and I are both her personal maids.
Even a maid is dressed so nicely.
The Zhen family must be very distinguished.
My Lady is waiting for you, and Mistress Zhen is home as well.
Please come inside.
Huan.
No need to be so formal.
I have no friends or family in Beijing.
I'm grateful to you for letting me stay here.
Now that you're here, I am your friend and family.
Please have a seat, Lady An.
Sit.
This is...
This is my aunt, Xiao.
She didn't want me to come to the capital alone.
Madam, please sit down.
Thank you.
I am deeply grateful for your kindness
to provide me a place to stay.
I am forever indebted to your compassionate care.
You're being courteous. Don't mention it.
How was the trip?
Don't even get me started.
The innkeeper treated Lady An like a rare treasure
and insisted on her staying for longer.
And I took care of it by scaring him off.
We owed it to Vermilion's quick wit.
Otherwise, the innkeeper would not have let us leave.
Vermilion is so clever.
That's all thanks to your guidance, Huan.
May I ask which month you were born in?
I'm seventeen, born on the 17th day of the fourth month.
I am sixteen, born on the 9th day of the second month.
You're younger. You will be my little sister then!
Yes. Anything you say, Elder Sister.
Huan'er.
Father, you are still up at this hour?
Have a seat.
Thanks.
You have been taking good care of Lady An.
I can tell my daughter is a dependable adult now.
There's something I haven't been able to discuss with you face to face.
But now I feel compelled to do so.
You must remember:
If you cannot ensure a place in His Majesty's affection,
you must hide your light and blunt your sharp thorns.
You are not expected to be His Majesty's
favorite and most distinguished concubine.
I simply wish my beloved daughter
a peaceful and pleasant life in the harem.
I seek not His Majesty's favor
but a steady life in the palace.
I shall protect the lives of my family clan and my own.
Good.
That's good.
As a rule, you are allowed dowry maids
who will accompany you in the palace.
They must be competent and more importantly, trustworthy.
Do you have anyone in mind?
I have thought about it.
Vermilion is quick-witted, and Jade has a meticulous mind.
I'd like to bring them.
They both grew up with you.
I can rest assured if they are in the palace with you.
Especially Jade, she is...
In fact, she is your sister.
My sister?
Your mother does not know...
Many years ago...
I met a Han woman...
And we... we had Jade.
No wonder when you brought Jade home,
you insisted she be my personal attendant.
It was not because of her mother's ethnicity...
She was the daughter of a convicted official.
If her identity is revealed,
it will not only harm your status but even ruin Jade's life.
I have done an injustice to your mother, and to Jade as well.
You did what you had to.
For Jade...
I will find a suitable family for her to marry.
If you have the heart to, I hope her fate will allow for it.
I have always treated her as my sister and always will.
Good.
My Lady is an imperial concubine now.
Yes.
I heard she is allowed to bring dowry maids to the palace.
And?
Are you going?
Where to?
The palace.
I will be wherever My Lady is.
We grew up together and will never split up.
Are you going?
I'm not sure.
My Lady treats you so well!
I'm not saying she doesn't.
I was just worried about who will take care of
Master and Mistress Zhen when we are gone.
Indeed. Master Zhen brought us home...
Aiya. Our concern is to serve My Lady.
We don't need to worry about Master and Mistress.
By the Grace of Heaven, His Majesty decrees:
"Zhen Yuandao's eldest daughter, Zhen Huan
is granted the title of Attendant, the seventh rank.
She is bestowed the honorary name Sourire.
Attendant Sourire will move in on the 15th day of the ninth month."
This is His Majesty's edict.
I thank His Majesty for the heavenly grace.
By the Grace of Heaven, His Majesty decrees:
"An Bihuai's daughter, An Lingrong
is granted the title of Companion, the eighth rank.
Companion An will move in on the 15th day of the ninth month."
This is His Majesty's edict.
I thank His Majesty for the heavenly grace.
You all may rise.
Mr. Zhen, Madam Orchid is an etiquette instructor in the palace.
Peace to you, Madam.
Attendant Sourire is very well-mannered.
She has an outstanding upbringing, Mr. Zhen.
Thank you for your flattering words, sir.
I'm not exaggerating.
I just came from Attendant Xia's family.
She gave the instructor quite an attitude.
(Madam Orchid)
I bow in respect before Attendant Sourire and Companion An.
Peace to My Ladies.
You are a respected madam from the palace.
We don't deserve you bowing to us.
Please do not bow to us while you're our teacher.
That's courteous of you, My Lady.
Sir, thank you for making the trip.
Especially on such a hot day.
Mistress, you are so generous.
Madam Orchid has served in the palace for many years.
She was an instructor for the prior emperor's concubines.
You both shall benefit greatly from her teaching.
Thank you, sir.
Since Attendant Sourire and Companion An are living together,
we won't send another instructor to live here.
I will trouble Madam Orchid to instruct them together,
and they can also learn from each other.
Yes, of course.
Sir, please come have some tea in the drawing room.
I can't. I have to visit the next family.
Please go ahead, sir.
Goodbye.
My Ladies, there were eight candidates selected this year.
The Manchu and the Mongolian Banners
will enter the palace before the Han Banners.
You two will move in on the same day as
Nobel Lady Shen, the daughter of the Commander of Jizhou Region.
The Commander of Jizhou Region?
Meizhuang is a Noble Lady!
We must congratulate her!
Yes.
The three of us can move in later
and look after one another when we're living in the palace.
Was that girl really so arrogant?
Xia Dongchun is bold because of her father's status.
Now that she has received the title of Attendant,
she even gave the etiquette instructor a lecture.
She probably possesses a bit of charm.
She's already a bully before entering the palace.
I will come face to face with her.
I heard that a girl got in her way on the selection day?
Who was it?
It was the daughter of the Deputy Minister of Judicial Review.
Her name is Zhen Huan.
His Majesty seems quite fond of her.
She was selected too and granted the title of Attendant.
The palace is sure to be lively from now on.
Tell the instructor at the Xia household
since her teaching is not appreciated,
she doesn't need to make much of an effort.
I believe the instructor already knows what to do.
They are all crying about deficits.
Taxes fall short every year.
Every province owes the court hundreds of thousands of taels.
The state is poor. The people are impoverished.
Where did all the money go?
May peace be restored in Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
in my humble opinion, the money finds its way
from the state to different destinations.
Hasn't Your Majesty heard
"A field has eight hundred owners every one thousand years"?
Your Majesty, please select a name tag.
Did I summon you in to clamor at me?
Your Majesty, it's the hour.
Attendant Joie.
Your Majesty is not aware.
Attendant Joie's name tag has been withdrawn.
I'm afraid it will not be presented for two months.
Why?
Consort Fleur said that Attendant Joie
has not fully recovered from her miscarriage
and so she is not suitable to serve Your Majesty overnight.
That's typical of Consort Fleur.
Never mind, I should let Attendant Joie recuperate.
I will visit Consort Fleur instead.
Yes.
His Majesty the Emperor.
Peace to Your Majesty.
Where is Consort Fleur? I didn't see her waiting for me outside.
Your Majesty, Her Highness was feeling unwell today
and has retired early.
She's already gone to bed at this hour?
If so, I suppose I shall leave now.
I shall visit Consort Astuce and the Third Prince.
If you leave, don't enter my palace gates again.
Somebody's in a mood tonight.
Your Majesty has not visited for so long.
You've probably forgotten your Shilan.
Nonsense.
How can I forget the only person
who can be so cheeky in front of me?
You smell nice.
It's the Pleasancy incense Your Majesty granted me exclusively.
I light it every day.
That is the scent that I like.
No one else deserves it.
The common households have their masters,
and the Forbidden City is the same.
However, there are only three proper masters:
Their Majesties the Empress Dowager, the Emperor, and the Empress.
The concubines are the minor mistresses.
The Emperor has one primary wife
and many secondary wives.
For example, Consort Fleur is in His Majesty's high favor,
but she is still a minor mistress.
You may call her "Your Highness" to show respect.
"Your Highness"?
Yes, but not everyone can bear this form of address.
The person must be the head of a palace
and ranked at Concubine or above.
The head of a palace lives in the main chamber
and takes charge of the matters in her palace.
The heads of palaces are fixed in number.
The lower ranks are flexible: Noble Lady, Attendant, and Companion.
Is Companion the lowest rank?
No, the lowest is Escort, the ninth rank.
I have heard of the nine ranks of officials,
and the ninth rank is as trivial as a sesame seed.
Turns out there are "sesame seed" concubines too.
What is an "Escort"?
Escorts are not much different than the maids,
but they can accompany His Majesty overnight.
They can be promoted to Companion if His Majesty pleases.
As per the ancestors' rules, a concubine
can only be promoted to the next rank above.
Huang Guiquan bows before Your Highness.
Rise.
I thank Your Highness.
Your Highness, the Empress has prepared
the residence assignments for the new concubines.
She asked me to read them to Your Highness.
Changes will be made if Your Highness finds anything inappropriate.
Go ahead.
Noble Lady Fuca, Manchu Plain White Banner,
the Palace of Prolonging Happiness.
Noble Lady Borjigin, Mongolian Bordered Red Banner,
the Palace of Accumulated Purity.
Noble Lady Shen, Han Bordered Yellow Banner,
the Palace of Universal Happiness.
Attendant Sourire, Han Plain Blue Banner,
the Palace of Celestial Favor.
Wait.
Attendant Sourire?
Yes, the daughter of Zhen Yuandao,
the Deputy Minister of Judicial Review.
She is the only new concubine who's been granted
an honorary name, although her rank is not high.
Was she the eloquent girl at the Selection?
Yes, Your Highness.
Was it His Majesty's decision to assign her
the Palace of Celestial Favor?
It was the decision of the Empress.
His Majesty doesn't oversee the assignment.
The Palace of Celestial Favor is spacious and ornate,
and close to His Majesty's Hall of Mental Cultivation.
The Empress is skilled at currying favor with His Majesty.
Anything His Majesty says is good,
she's never late to sing its praises.
She's growing old like a browning pearl,
and wants assistance from the young concubines.
Giving her the Palace of Celestial Favor...
So she can absorb all His Majesty's "celestial favor"?
Now, I will tell you about His Majesty the Emperor.
His Majesty is the fourth son of the prior emperor.
He was titled State Prince Yong
and first married in his estate.
He married the current Empress Dowager's cousin's daughter.
His wife had a gentle nature and was well-respected.
She was deeply in love with His Majesty.
Unfortunately, she passed away due to difficult labor
three years after the wedding.
And the newborn prince was lost as well.
His Majesty still grieves her death to this day.
He honored her posthumously as Empress Première.
His Majesty is an Emperor of everlasting love.
What about... the current Empress?
I heard that she is the daughter of a secondary wife.
One's blessings are not to be judged by the status of their mother.
Her Majesty has a noble character and is "the Mother of the Nation."
I misspoke.
Her Majesty was the Lord Consort when she married.
She is the younger sister of Empress Première.
She became the primary wife after Empress Première's passing.
His Majesty holds her in high esteem.
Are there other palaces suitable for occupancy?
There are...
The Palace of Pearl Jade is vacant and clean.
It was occupied by Noble Lady Parfum.
But it's smaller, and out of the way.
Not only that, it used to be a theater.
The prior emperor didn't like going the distance for operas,
and it became the residence for concubines who lost favor.
Besides, the chamber is now considered bad luck.
Bad luck?
Lady Parfum had a miscarriage and
later was banished to the Cold Palace.
That's not about her luck.
If the new Attendant is fortunate enough
to conceive an heir like Noble Lady Parfum,
the Empress will be even more pleased.
Yes, Your Highness.
Is the chamber occupied by anyone else?
Not yet.
Tidy it up
and Attendant Sourire will be received there.
Also, what about Xia?
The girl His Majesty pointed at offhandedly
and said she had an interesting name.
Yes,
the Empress requested His Majesty to also grant her
the title of Attendant considering her father's rank.
Sounds like the Empress elevated her status to show favor.
I can't say for certain.
Keep an eye out in case she's in league with the Empress.
Send her to live with Noble Lady Fuca.
She'll learn to behave.
I heard that Consort Fleur is the most favored wife.
Yes, Her Highness is the younger sister of Great General Nian.
She has been exclusively favored
since she entered the family as Lord Consort.
Consort Fleur is in high favor, but why isn't Her Highness
ranked at Noble Consort or Imperial Noble Consort?
Good question. Allow me to explain.
Because Her Highness has no children.
Her Highness is already ranked at Consort
without having a single child.
And so we say she is in high favor.
But favor is not the most important.
Your priority should be producing an heir.
If not a son, then a daughter will do.
Otherwise, you won't have someone to rely on your whole life.
Ah, of course,
Consort Fleur is young and healthy.
She will certainly have children since she is highly favored.
I heard that Consort Fleur is
"endowed with beauty that could topple a nation."
She's the foremost of the Han Banners.
Perhaps even including the Manchu and Mongolian Banners,
no one can compare to Her Highness's "thousand demeanors of a phoenix."
Is that why her favor tops the harem?
Poet Li Bai wrote
"If love blossoms from a pretty face,
how can it flourish for long?"
[booklet of residence assignment]
Your Majesty, Consort Fleur changed
Attendant Sourire's residence to the Palace of Pearl Jade.
Unfortunate girl.
It's quite an isolated location, and not well furnished.
It used to be an opera house before.
And Noble Lady Parfum lived there.
How can Consort Fleur be so domineering?
She didn't even consult Your Majesty.
Did you not know her before today?
But His Majesty likes her for the way she is.
Here's another gray hair.
Whose name tag did His Majesty flip tonight?
His Majesty had a busy day and
stayed in the Hall of Mental Cultivation.
He is probably still awake.
That's just as well.
His Majesty is fond of Attendant Sourire.
Since her palace has a shade of gloom,
have sweet olives planted in her yard to ward off bad luck.
Yes, Your Majesty. I will have it done properly.
"The gates of the palace go as deep as the ocean."
This was no more than a saying to me...
You must take care of yourself
and live cautiously among the other concubines.
Don't bring yourself into conflicts.
Especially Consort Fleur, she's the most prominent.
If you... had the fortune to become a favored consort,
we would all be glad.
But that is not as important as your life.
I will always behave with propriety.
I won't let Father and Mother worry about me.
Yurao, I'll be gone soon.
Please take care of Father and Mother for me.
Understand?
I understand.
My Lady, it's almost the hour to leave.
I have to go now.
Father and Mother, please take care.
Theme: The Phoenix Taking Flight
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support or join us: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
The dreams I dimly recall;
The past I hardly remember,
amidst the autumn moons and the spring flowers.
Like the moon's reflection on water
or flowers seen through mist - floating and drifting.
The joyous sounds you brought;
The silence you left;
Changing faster than clouds can turn to rain.
Our minds resonated;
Our hearts beat in unison;
But we lost what we once possessed.
A poem to converse;
A melody to accompany;
A heart to bind to mine.
I hoped for endless longing and eternal promise,
but I’m left with only the flute and the zither.
With affection, I pleased;
With my heart, I committed;
With my arms, I embraced.
I desired to be remembered;
Desired to be cherished;
Why am I only hated and deceived?
My wish ran against my will.
Behold the mockery of destiny and the game of fate.
My unwavering love is gone
like flowers swept away in the wind.
Praying for a bright moon;
Praying for a rising sun;
Dreaming to bask in the spring breezes.
But the unsparing northern winds carry snow and rain
to destroy the aspirations of the plum tree.
A phoenix about to take flight rustles its wings
but the arc of its flight is unseen.
The phoenix tree sways in the wind,
shedding memories in the whispers of the falling leaves.